Subtitles by explosiveskull
Huh? Oh!
Ooh!
Nearly there, Hognob.
Nearly there.
Just a bit farther.
Try a little bit harder.
We can do it.
Just a little bit more, Hognob.
I can reach it.
Got it.
Still got it.
Hognob, enough!
Oi, enough now!
Mammoths! Come on, Hognob.
Let's go wake Bobnar.
Hey, Chief.
Chief!
What? What? What?
Are you awake, Chief?
Chief?
Time to go hunting.
Bit early, isn't it, Dug?
But, Chief, we're early man.
Come on, everyone.
Time to get up.
Morning, everyone.
Morning, Chief.
Bit nippy this morning.
Ow! Ow!
Ow!
Oops. Sorry.
Wait, Chief. Chief...
Chief.
So I've been thinking.
You know we always hunt rabbits?
Yeah. Very tasty they are, too.
Yes, but couldn't we
try hunting something,
well, you know, bigger?
What, like a hare?
No, like a buffalo or a mammoth.
You want us to hunt a
five-ton, bone-crushing mammoth?
Yeah. Why not?
I really believe
we could do it, Chief.
Dug, look at our ancestors.
You don't see them
hunting big things, do you?
They hunted little round beasts.
Of some sort.
Yeah, what are
those things anyway?
Don't know.
I suppose they couldn't
draw rabbits back then.
Wait. Sorry, no, Chief.
Chief,
about the mammoth thing...
Look, I'll tell you what, I'll
definitely bear it in mind.
All right?
Come on, Dug.
Right, gather round.
Grab a spear.
Oh! It's pointy!
- Oh, Treebor. Just get over there.
- Aw, Mum!
- Morning, Barry.
- Morning, Dug.
Mr. Rock coming hunting today?
Oh, yeah, wouldn't miss it
for the world.
Morning, Asbo.
Change your underpants today?
Yeah! Changed them
with Thongo, Chief.
Champion!
Mmm.
- Chief.
- Yes, Gravelle?
When I put my arm up, it hurts.
Well, don't do it, then.
Grubup, don't eat that.
That's Eemak.
Yum!
Exactly. Uh... Right.
Heads down, everyone.
Thank you, Dug.
Shh!
We give thanks for our valley,
our home,
this precious ground,
which sustains us
and gives us shelter
from the Badlands.
May we live in peace, balance,
and harmony with our forest
and all the creatures
we share it with.
Right, let's go kill something.
A rabbit!
That's it. That's it.
I've got him.
To you, Eemak.
Ouch.
Nice try, though.
Let's use
an element of surprise.
Righto, Chief.
Ow!
I got him!
No, I haven't!
Great! Champion!
Got you!
Whoa!
I got this, Gravelle.
Ha-hey!
Well done, Mr. Rock!
Nice job, everyone.
Rabbit surprise tonight!
See, Dug?
We hunt rabbits,
everyone's happy.
Although the thing
about rabbits, Chief,
well, they are quite small.
Dug, Dug. Look at us...
You seriously think
we could catch a mammoth?
Nice moves, Mr. Rock.
Us lot?
You've been practicing.
Shush, everyone.
The rabbits are fighting back!
I don't think this is rabbits.
Attack!
Run!
Mr. Rock!
No!
To the Badlands!
What, leave the valley?
Come on. Just run.
Hognob!
Where's Dug?
Have you seen Dug?
- Go on.
- Thank you, Chief.
Dug!
Hmm...
Excellent.
All right, secure the valley.
Start mining ore.
Or what, Lord Nooth?
Ore, you fool!
Start mining the ore.
The metal that's in the ground.
Oh, the ore! In the ground.
Yes.
What about the primitives?
Oh, let them rot
in The Badlands.
They are
the low-achievers of history
with their puny flints
and their drafty caves.
You've picked the wrong
tribe to mess with.
Oh, I am so scared!
You are waving your stones about!
The Age of Stone is over, Dino.
Long live the Age of Bronze!
Oh.
Okay, let's get moving.
Of course, Lord Nooth.
I'm late for my massage.
Huh?
Uh...
What are you doing?
Get out of the way!
Hey! Hey!
Multi-purpose pen swords!
Very handy
for opening bottles, too!
Sliced bread. Wow!
That's the best thing since...
Well, ever!
Oh!
Hmm.
Hey!
- Huh?
- Don't touch the bronze.
- The what?
- The bronze!
Where have you been,
the Stone Age?
Oh. Uh...
What?
Fifty schnookels!
Voluntary contribution.
Everyone has to pay!
It's gone up again.
- It's daylight robbery!
- Fifty schnookels!
Voluntary contribution!
Hey! She hasn't
voluntarily contributed.
Hmm? Stop her!
- Hey. Hey.
- Oi! Stop her!
Whoa!
Hmm?
Hello. Oh!
Sorry!
I tell you,
I wouldn't want to
be facing me out there.
Hey, Hügelgraber,
can't you see in that thing?
The arena's this way.
You girls are gonna
get slaughtered.
Let's go!
All stand for our mighty
leader, Lord Nooth!
Who challenges the champions?
We challenge the champions!
We accept the challenge!
The hour has come.
Let the sacred game commence!
Introducing Real Bronzio
and the captain, Jurgend!
Today's match official,
Referee Dino!
In the name of Queen Oofeefa,
we give thanks
for the beautiful game.
Oggy! Oggy! Oggy!
Oi! Oi! Oi!
Let's play football!
Whilst I count my schnookels.
Hügelgraber!
What are you doing?
Get in the goal!
What's up with Hügelgraber?
Come on!
Pick it up! Pick it up!
To me! To me!
What? Put it down!
Put it down!
Free kick!
Hügelgraber!
Just get in the game!
Just kick it!
Huh?
What are you doing, Hügelgraber?
You just scored an own goal!
He's not me!
Huh?
Oh!
A caveman?
- A caveman?
Playing the sacred game?
Bring him here.
How dare you...
Oh.
How dare you set foot
on our hallowed ground?
You took our ground.
- Our home!
- Oh, that.
Listen, you Stone Age brute.
You have no home.
Your kind are finished
on this Earth.
Now take him away and kill him.
Slowly.
Argh! No, I mean
take him away at normal speed
and kill him slowly. Idiots!
Now get on with the game.
We challenge the champions!
Wait... Wait!
Huh?
What did you say?
- He said, "We challenge..."
- I heard what he said!
If we win, we keep our valley.
You leave my tribe in peace.
Hmm.
You think you can beat us
at football?
A match between
the Bronze and the brutes?
What an idea!
Sacrilege, O Premier Leader!
Yes. Quite.
The masses would flock to see
such a vulgar spectacle. Pah!
Hmm...
Oh!
Really?
For the valley, you say?
Hmm?
- Dug!
- It's Dug!
He's alive!
Uh, what's that crazy fruit
he's got?
"Football"?
What's "football"?
And how's it going to get
our valley back?
Well, it's this amazing game,
Chief.
And the leader
of the Bronze people,
he says if we play this game
and beat them at it...
Ooh, nice tight shorts!
Aw, Mum!
We can have our valley back.
That's what we want.
- And if we don't beat them?
- Ah.
Well, then,
he said we'll spend the rest
of our miserable lives
working down a mine.
No!
- What's a "mine"?
- Dug,
we've never even played
this game.
But that's just it.
We did. Once.
Huh?
Those cave paintings
back in our valley,
they're pictures of our
ancestors playing football.
- Champion!
- So if they did it,
surely we can do it.
Sorry! Shimmering memories
make me sneeze.
This doesn't change anything,
Dug.
It's just too risky.
Oh, come on, Chief!
We can do it, Chief!
I wanna play football!
I wanna play now!
Now!
Listen...
No, we're not... No!
All right, then.
Don't worry about us.
Yeah, we'll...
We'll be okay.
We'll just die a slow and
lingering death in the Badlands.
Huh?
Come on, Chief.
Just give us a chance. Please!
Look, all right.
Maybe we'll give this
"football" idea a try, then.
No promises, mind.
The match is to be played
at the full moon.
And then we go back
to the valley!
Sweet!
Right, line up,
everybody! In line!
- All yours, Dug.
- Thanks, Chief.
All right!
- Um...
Are hogs supposed
to play football?
No. Oh...
Probably not, no.
Sorry, Hognob.
This is a football.
One side tries to kick
the ball into this goal.
Ooh.
And the other side tries
to kick the ball in that goal.
Ahh!
Football sounds hard.
What happens if you kick
the ball in the goal?
Well, if you kick the ball
in the goal,
then other men hug and kiss you.
- Oh.
- Mmm.
Right, who wants to try?
I'll give it a go.
- Nice one.
- Aw, Mum!
Good, Magma. All right, okay, good.
Right. Um...
So I'm...
I'm gonna try and get the ball,
and you have to stop me, okay?
Come on, come on!
Ow!
- Nice one, Mum!
- Football's brilliant.
That can't be right.
Surely, you can't hit
other players?
No, you're supposed
to attack the ball.
No, no, no, no, not weapons!
Just use fist?
No! No fighting at all.
- Where's the fun in that?
- Uh...
Hmm.
Okay, Thongo!
Oh!
Ooh!
- Oh!
- Yes!
Good effort. Great.
Okay, next.
Huh?
Hognob.
Go for it, Asbo.
Yay!
Oh...
Excuse me!
Can we have our ball back,
please?
Huh. Hmm.
Trust me, Dino.
This football match between
the Stone Age
and the Bronze World,
it's perfect!
- Oh, how I love it!
- Yes, football.
No.
Bronze!
Mmm.
So cold and hard and slippery.
Ooh.
And this game is going
to make me loads of it.
Your Premiership,
what if the Queen finds out?
That old crow?
She doesn't know
what goes on out here.
Luckily.
Delivering message!
Your Footballness,
it's a Message Bird.
Huh?
Ugh. Well, go on, make it...
"Hello? Hello?"
"How do you use
this Message Bird thing?"
It's the Queen.
"Just speak into its ear, ma'am."
"It will mimic
everything it hears."
"I don't even know if
I'm holding it the... Testing!"
"Testing!"
"Nooth? Nooth?"
Perhaps she's heard
about the game.
Of course she hasn't
heard about the game.
"I've heard about the game.
- "You, arranging a football
match against a bunch of savages?
"You idiot!"
"Imagine if we lost."
- We won't.
- "I said, imagine it!"
"Exactly!"
"The mighty Bronze Age"
"brought to its knees
by a bunch of cavemen?"
"Well, I'm warning you, Nooth."
"You'd better not lose."
"Hmm?"
End of message.
Oh! Hmm.
Silly old bat!
How dare she talk
to me like that!
"Silly old bat!"
"How dare she talk
to me like that?"
Delivering message!
Guards! Get that bird back!
What does the Queen know anyway?
The cavemen are oafs.
My players are...
Overpaid?
Champions!
Oh, yes, champions.
They spend their days thinking,
sleeping, eating football.
And I hardly think
the cavemen will be doing that.
Rise and shine!
Training time!
Ow!
No, not like that.
When I said "free kick,"
I meant of the ball.
Sorry, Dug.
Hognob, no!
Barry, where are you going?
No, don't wander off!
Football's hard.
Dug, my toe hurts!
Grubup, drop it!
I told you,
it's the only one we've got.
Come on, everyone!
We should be able to do this.
No, don't... Don't sit down.
Grubup no like football.
Make Grubup hungry.
Oh. Oh, ho-ho.
Food. Yum!
Huh?
Oh...
Duck! Duck!
Huh?
No! Duck!
Look!
It's a giant man-eating mallard!
Run away!
Huh?
You haven't eaten
your primordial soup.
Not really hungry.
Oh...
Huh?
Dug, it's time to give up
this football lark
for their sake.
They're just not capable of it.
Don't you miss the valley,
Chief?
The valley's gone now.
And we're better off
here in the Badlands
than slaving down some mine.
I mean, there's
the odd giant duck around,
but at least
we're still together.
We're still a tribe.
But our ancestors
played football.
We know they did.
I still believe we can do this.
With what?
You haven't even got
a ball to play with.
It's over.
No. There's still time.
Come on, Hognob.
Okay, Hognob. Hognob?
Huh?
Right.
Let's go get some balls.
Shh!
Ow!
What strange magic is this?
Hognob. You stay.
I don't want
to attract attention.
Huh?
What's all that
crashing around out there?
Is that you, Stefano?
Huh?
Stop messing about
and get in here
with those firm hands of yours.
Uh...
Come on, Stefano!
It's time for my massage.
And the exciting new signing
picks the ball up
in the center circle.
She beats one,
nutmegs another,
lobs it neatly over
the big fullback.
She's going all the way.
She shoots!
She scores!
Yeah!
And the crowd goes wild!
Goal!
Ah, I need this, Stefano.
I'm feeling stressed.
An hardworking governor like me,
stuck out in
this miserable wasteland?
He deserves a few perks.
Simple pleasures like fine food,
a massage,
his own champion football team.
Well, come on, chop-chop,
I haven't got all day.
Oh, my tendons are like ropes.
You can go the whole hog.
Hmm?
You're that crazy caveman guy.
The angry pan girl.
What are you doing here,
caveman?
This is the sacred turf.
No one's allowed here.
- Balls.
- Huh?
I need balls.
You came all this way
and broke into the stadium
just to find some balls?
Wow.
You're pretty brave, caveman.
And stupid.
Actually,
more stupid than brave, really.
Thanks.
I'm Goona, by the way.
Dug.
Come on, I can help.
Ahh, ohh, eee...
That's good!
Mmm.
I don't know what
the Queen is worrying about.
I mean, we all know
what losers cavemen are.
Those Stone Age dolts couldn't
beat their own grandmothers.
Brainless goons!
Gormless halfwits!
Stefano! Not so ham-fisted!
In fact, enough massage.
How about
some relaxing music instead?
Huh?
I envy you.
- Me?
- The chance to play
on that pitch, the sacred turf,
in front of thousands of fans!
Well, maybe you will one day.
You think they let girls play
for Real Bronzio?
You really are crazy.
Why do you think
I sneak in here?
Who is that?
Scarper!
Stop! Thieves!
This way!
They went that way!
- Huh?
- No! That way!
Give me those, quick!
Ow!
You're really good!
Thanks!
I do a lot of practice.
Oh, I've just had a great idea!
Come on!
Huh?
What on Earth's
got into you tonight, Stefano?
- Stefano?
- Yes, sir?
Huh?
Hognob!
Hognob, meet Goona.
Goona, Hognob.
Hi, Hognob.
Sire, are you all right?
Of course I'm not all right,
you idiot!
I've just been massaged
by a pig!
Wake up, everyone.
I want you all to meet someone.
This is Goona.
Hi!
And she's gonna help us
win the game.
- Oh.
- Why would she do that?
She gets to play
on the sacred turf
in front of thousands of fans.
Whoa.
Glad to be on board.
So what formation
do you normally play?
Um... Formation?
4-4-2 or 4-3-3?
Who's your sweeper?
Um...
Do you man-mark or play zonally?
Uh...
We just kick the ball about
and chase it.
You think you can beat
Real Bronzio
just by chasing a ball around?
You need to know
what you're up against.
This is Jurgend, the captain.
Best goal-scorer
in the known world.
- Knows it too.
- Ha!
Their winger, Lightning Hammer.
Never strikes twice
in the same place.
Midfield dynamo Qwik Wun Tu.
He can kick faster
than you can think.
Fullback, Gonad the Gaul.
No one gets past his tackle.
- Oh!
- Aw, Mum!
Make no mistake.
These are the best players
bronze can buy.
They're like ginormous
great big footballing giants!
Oh, there's no way we can beat
such a great team.
They may be great,
but what they're not is a team.
They're 11 players
who each think they're the star.
That's their weakness.
And that's how
you can beat them.
- Oh.
- Hmm.
Goona's right.
They may be better
players than us,
but we have something
they don't.
- Huh?
- Moss?
No, Barry, not moss.
We've got each other.
And if we work together,
then maybe we can do this.
Right. We've got
a lot of hard work to do.
And we haven't even got
a full team.
Oh, oh!
What's going on?
Oh, Chief, this is Goona,
and she's going to
help us win the game.
I thought we're done
with football.
Not now you've turned up.
You're in the team.
I'm not playing.
I'm an old man.
I'm nearly 32.
Okay, that is old.
- Go in goal.
- Ow!
Right, well,
that's settled, then.
Now, where's
your training facilities?
Real Bronzio have the very best.
And all we've got is
the Badlands.
Three, two, one.
This way, everyone!
Wait! What? Oh!
What are you doing?
That way, everyone!
Ow! Ah! Ooh!
This is a bit dangerous.
What are you... What the...
Eh? Well, I'll be...
Okay. Pass and move.
It's very important
that you pass and move.
But whatever happens,
keep your formation.
Oh! Oh!
Ooh!
Nice one, Asbo!
That's it!
Everyone working together!
Ugh! This is all I need.
You found these
in the primitives' valley?
It seems their ancestors
were playing football
centuries before we were.
The Queen must not find out
about this, all right?
Delivering message!
Oh, no.
"What's this"
"I hear about the savages"
"playing football
centuries before we were?"
Ow! Ow! I didn't know! Ow!
"And my spies tell me
they're getting better.
- Ow!
- "Training every day!"
Ow! Ow! Ow!
"You better not screw it up,
Nooth, or else,"
"I'll tell you who'll be
going down the mine."
"You will!"
This has gone far enough.
They're Stone Age brutes.
They live in caves.
They eat mud! No.
I need to shut them down.
Mess with their
tiny cavemen minds.
Brilliant! How do we do that?
I don't know.
The answer isn't just going
to walk in the door.
Sire, we've found something else
down in the new mine
in the valley.
We've made a copy
for your inspection.
Oh! Ow!
That's perfect.
Mmm.
Hognob.
Whoa! Great save, Chief!
You know, we may just
stand a chance tomorrow.
A small chance,
but a chance.
If our ancestors did it,
so can we.
Hey, hey, not bad for 32, eh?
I never thought
I'd say this, Dug,
but we're pretty good.
Oi, oi, oi! That's mine.
I've got it.
Soon be home.
Huh?
No!
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Calm down, caveman.
I just wanted you
to see our new mine.
After all, you'll soon be digging
lots of bronze out of it.
Oh, we're not going down
any mine, mammoth-mouth.
Ah, yes.
Because you're
great footballers,
just like your ancestors.
You... You know about them?
Bronze is not all
we found down here.
What... What...
More cave paintings?
Yes.
Only these ones tell
the whole story.
You see, your ancestors
did not just play football.
They invented the game.
You even taught
other tribes how to play.
But you had one problem.
No matter how hard you tried,
you just always ended up losing,
match after match,
game after game.
In fact, after many, many moons,
you just gave up altogether.
It was all too painful for you.
It turns out your tribe
were totally crap at football.
You're losers, caveman.
Always have been.
Always will be.
No.
No, it can't be true.
Do you really believe
you can beat us tomorrow?
Face it, caveman.
You and your tribe,
you just don't have it in you.
But I'm willing
to offer you a deal.
A way out.
Time to turn in.
Big day tomorrow.
- Come on, Treebor!
- Night, Goona!
Can I sleep in me football kit?
- Night, everyone!
Huh?
Think it over, caveman,
because the mine is waiting
for you and
your primitive friends.
Oh! Me arm hurts!
Oh!
Where are you, Mum?
You idiot!
What have you done?
At the end of the day,
we're just
a rabbit-hunting tribe.
I'm sorry, Chief!
I didn't mean
for this to happen.
Bobnar, you've got
to believe me!
Huh?
Oh, Hognob!
Oh!
My dear old hoggy friend.
What if I'm wrong?
What if Chief was right
all along?
Huh?
What if we are just
a tribe of rabbit-hunters?
Uh...
Forgive me, Hognob.
But I've got a deal to make.
I've got to save the tribe.
Huh?
Get your cuddly caveman here!
Before they go extinct!
One hundred schnookels!
Voluntary contribution.
Everyone has to pay.
One hundred schnookels!
- It has doubled!
- Voluntary contribution!
- Everyone has to pay.
- This is outrageous!
Have you got change
for a dinner plate?
It's all going to plan, Dino.
Ooh. I love you,
little bronze coin.
Hello!
I love you. I love you too.
And you too.
Nooth!
What are you doing?
Ugh. Not that stupid
old bird again.
Tell Chef to boil it up
in a cassoulet.
"Stupid old bird"?
"Cassoulet"?
Oh!
Your Majesty!
Why, this is an unexpected
pleasure.
Thought I'd come
to this caveman game myself.
And have a little nose.
A great honor, Your Majesty.
And you have to say, Brian,
Real Bronzio's manager
is on the back foot.
Oh, it's a terrible
start for the lad, Bryan.
Terrible. I mean, just awful.
I put it down
to pre-match nerves.
You're not wrong there, Brian.
I've brought
my royal commentators with me.
Sit!
Right.
Well, let's start the fun,
shall we?
Bring out
the Stone Age challengers!
What? Where are you taking me?
What on Earth are
you playing at?
Oh, Dug.
Who challenge the champions?
You'll leave
my people alone as agreed?
Yes, just say the words.
Not me.
I forfeit the game
and volunteer myself
for the mines.
And?
And our valley
is yours.
My goodness!
Have the cavemen caved?
Oh! So it seems.
How very disappointing.
Everyone, go home!
There is no game.
Apologies for the inconvenience.
Tell the staff, no refunds.
Fowl! Fowl!
Foul? No one's even playing,
you silly slap-head!
No, fowl!
Well, Brian,
it looks like the Stone Age
team have just flown in.
That's right, Bryan.
They're definitely looking
good in the air!
See what I did there?
Oh, goodie.
Seems there is a game after all.
Gonna start without us, Dug?
Chief, we can't play this game.
What, because of
a few paintings?
So you know about
those terrible pictures?
They are terrible.
I can draw better than that.
But that's all they are.
Pictures.
It's this lot that counts.
You were right, Dug.
I thought
we were just rabbit-hunters.
Well, not anymore.
You've shown me that.
Who's playing with Dug
for the valley?
Champion.
It's what Mr. Rock
would've wanted.
We challenge the champions!
Your funeral, caveman!
This may be
an uneven contest, Brian,
but let's hope
it's at least entertaining.
Ha! Let's get this done.
What?
Let's do it!
Oh! Well, this is interesting.
Hey, Hügelgraber!
Wake up!
Very interesting!
Huh?
I don't believe it,
Bryan! The Stone Age team
have caught
their opponents napping.
Beginners' luck, Your Majesty.
Hmph.
Bad move, caveman.
Now you've just made us mad.
Oh!
Yay!
And normal service is restored!
Jurgend! Jurgend!
Let's see the replay, Bryan.
Ooh, ja, kick!
Yay! Goal!
You can't argue
with the puppets, Bryan.
Kissy-kissy!
Hug, hug, hug!
Aye,
the puppets don't lie, Brian.
Oh!
Oh! Ah,
and that's a goal.
That's two.
Real Bronzio are in
- no mood to compromise.
- Goal!
Never mind. Come on, everyone!
Boo!
And surely, that's settled it.
Yay!
Well, it's halftime,
Bryan, and Real Bronzio
are dominating this match.
♪ You're going down the mine!
♪ You're going down the mine! ♪
The only place we're going
is back to the valley.
Now come on, everyone!
Let's show them what we've got!
Remember your training, Eemak!
Nice one, Eemak! That's it!
Goodness me, it looks
like a caveman counterattack.
Come on, then.
Let's see your tackle.
Great work, Magma!
Hey, hey!
What was that?
Oh-ho!
Unorthodox, Bryan,
but effective.
- This is unprecedented!
- Yay!
I can't remember any side
scoring two goals
against Real Bronzio.
Oh, you fool.
What were you playing at?
You silly, stupid...
Idiot! Do I have to do
everything around here?
Caveman coming through!
Nibbles, Your Majesty?
Stuff your nibbles!
Well, Real Bronzio,
they just don't know what's
hit them, they really don't.
Oh-ho! The Stone Age team
is really coming together, Bryan.
You're not wrong,
Brian. It's like early man
united. That's another joke
there, Brian.
Oh, look at this!
The Stone Age striker beats one,
nutmegs another...
All yours, Goona!
Hmm.
She's going all the way.
She shoots.
She scores!
The crowd are going wild!
- And who can blame them?
- Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Wait a minute!
She shouldn't even be
on the pitch.
And why not?
Because she's a...
A great player!
You lot!
Get your act together!
Unless you want to be suspended
for the rest of the season.
Play on!
Hmm...
- Psst. Dino! Dino!
- Eh?
- Have you got your rule book handy?
- Of course.
Good. Because
I'm throwing it at you.
Eh?
Come on, everyone.
One last goal will take us home.
Dino is having a lie-down.
I am the new ref.
Well, that's not fair!
Oh, isn't it?
Let's ask the new ref.
Ref, is it fair?
Oh, yes, it's totally fair.
Okay. Play on!
It's injury time. Understand?
- Ooh!
- Oh, that's not cricket, Bryan.
Whatever cricket is.
Nothing to see there. Play on.
- No!
- I didn't see anything.
No foul! Play on!
No, no. Get up. Play on.
Oh, that's way below the belt.
Chief!
Oh, caveman down, Brian!
Oh, my leg! Oh, my leg!
Hurts so bad!
Penalty!
Jurgend should get
a prize for acting.
Chief? Chief?
Ha! I soon have it fixed.
Oh, great.
Um... Huh?
Ha. There. Good job.
Come on,
that was never a penalty!
Fine.
Check the replay.
Oh, kick, ahh! Referee!
Oh, my leg! My leg!
Oh, no, the crocodile!
Snack, snack, snack.
Oh, terrible foul!
Beating him with sausages!
Shame on you.
Definite penalty.
A draw is just not good enough
for the primitive part-timers, Bryan.
And now this.
A Real Bronzio penalty
in the dying moments
of the match.
Aye, and the goalie
looks in a bad way too.
Dug...
Chief?
I spent my whole life
hunting rabbits.
I held you back.
I'm sorry.
I'm so...
Chief?
Chief!
Huh?
Dug,
I don't mean to worry you, but what
are we going to do for a goalie?
Hognob?
Okay!
My word. Is that a pig
they just put in goal?
Have to say that's rather rash.
- Rasher. Do you get it? Bacon.
- Mmm.
I've never missed a penalty.
Not against a pig anyway.
And it looks like it's all over
for this plucky band
of knuckle-grazers, Bryan.
A great effort,
but, in the end,
it wasn't quite enough.
Say goodbye
to your valley, caveman.
Come on, Hognob.
You can do it.
He's got a trotter to it!
It's still in play, Brian.
Dug. Dug!
You were always
a mammoth-hunter!
Dug! Over here!
Go hunt mammoth!
Everyone! Give me a hand!
My ball!
Don't crowd me!
That is an amazing goal!
Yay!
Look at that.
The giant duck is on the pitch.
He thinks it's all over.
It is now!
Is this as good as you imagined?
No.
It's better!
Yeah!
Well done, my old hoggy friend!
You cheat!
You are a disgrace to football!
Oh!
Hmm?
Good game.
Ja.
Well played, caveman.
So...
Huh?
You've reminded us how the
beautiful game should be played.
As for Lord Nooth...
Nooth? Nooth! Where is that...
- Rat!
- Yes, quite!
Guards!
Apprehend that rodent!
So long, suckers!
My word, Bryan.
That schnookel-grabbing
scoundrel
is making off with the profits!
After you.
Aye, but will he get away?
- Oh, superb shot!
- And a rebound!
Oh, that got him!
Aye, Nooth is on
the back foot now, Brian.
Quite literally.
Look at that.
- Caught by the old bill.
- Oh, Bryan,
that's comedy bronze.
Well done, my friend.
No! My lovely schnookels!
Yay!
Oh, refund.
That should remind him
of the pecking order, eh?
Yeah.
Oh, and, caveman,
I think this is yours.
Symbol of a game sent
from heaven.
Thank you, Your...
Bronze Chiefness.
And now, I believe
it's time you went home,
to your valley.
We're going home.
Oh, hey!
Subtitles by explosiveskull